前情提要
Previously...
你不需要怕我
Ye need not be scared of me,
也不用怕任何一个人 我在你的身边
nor anyone else here, so long as I'm with you.
你该上路了
You're coming on the road.
带上一名医生才是明智之举
I think it would be wise to have a healer along.
你有看到你的苏格兰同伴
Have you seen any of your Scottish companions
筹钱谋反的么
raise funds for the rebellion?
队长  我拒绝再回答了
Captain, I refuse to submit further to this interrogation.
你没有任何权利对这女人那样
You have no right to that woman.
现在她该处在我的保护之下了
Now, she must be returned to me for protection.
恐怕会有更多的问题了
I'm afraid further questions have arisen.
必须要赶在明天日落之前
Be sure to deliver her to Fort William
将她送到威廉那儿
by sundown tomorrow.
除非你不是英格兰人 而是苏格兰人
I can only legally refuse to hand you back to Randall
我才能拒绝把你交回给兰德尔
if I can change you from an English woman to a Scot.
-杜戈尔想让我们结婚 -我知道
- Dougal wants us to be married. - I know.
可是 你不会嫌弃我不是处女么
Well, doesn't it bother you that I'm not a virgin?
不 只要你别介意我还是个处男
No, so long as it doesna bother you that... I am.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
翻译：呆毛 小P Windy 考拉 香蕉奶昔
压制：hhjie 时轴：Sasa 总监：Jophy
校对：Jophy
外乡人第一季  第七集
准备好了么
Ready?
准备什么
For what?
各就位
Right, then, folks.
真好看
Lovely.
现在
Now?
有何不可
Why not?
你父母呢
What about your parents?
他们在酒店等我们呢
They've been waiting for us at the restaurant.
就让他们等着吧
Let them wait.
弗兰克 他们到现在还没见过我
Frank, they've never even met me.
那又怎样
Yeah, so?
他们也不会看见克莱尔 毕彻姆
They'll never meet Claire Beauchamp.
他们将要见的是
I will have the pleasure of introducing them
兰德尔夫人
to Mrs. Frank Randall.
你这个小疯子
You... you're mad.
你确定不去教堂举办一场盛大的婚礼
Are you sure you wouldn't rather a big church wedding or...
不 不
No, no.
我确定
I'm sure.
如果你的家人喜欢呢
Maybe your family would prefer it.
亲爱的 我唯一在乎的家人是你
Darling, the only family I care about is you.
还有我们一起打造的家
And the family that we will make together.
你愿意嫁给我么
Will you marry me?
当然
Of course.
你可以亲吻你的新郎了
You may kiss yer bride.
不久 你就会遗忘
You forget your life after awhile...
你之前的生活了
the life you had before.
你视若珍宝的东西
Things you cherish and hold dear
就像珍珠链子
are like pearls on a string.
一旦切断 珍珠就会散落一地
Cut the knot, they scatter across the floor,
滚落到角落 再也找不到
rolling into dark corners, never to be found again.
然后你就继续你现在的生活
So you move on.
最终 你就会彻底忘记
And eventually you forget
珍珠究竟是什么样子了
what the pearls even looked like.
或者 你试图想 也想不起来了
Or at least you try.
婚礼好像还在举行
Sounds like the wedding party is still going strong.
他们好像还不着急睡觉
Don't suppose they're going to bed anytime soon.
对
No.
除非他们认为我们入睡了
Not until they know we've made things official.
他们不想看就好了
Should be grateful they didn't want to watch.
只有鲁伯特和安格斯想看
Only Rupert and Angus.
开玩笑的
A wee joke.
你可真像鲍勃霍普啊
You're a regular Bob Hope.
他很有趣么
Was he a funny man?
我是这么觉得的
I always thought so.
-要喝一杯么 -好的
- Perhaps a drink? - Aye.
敬一位淑女
To a... A lady of grace,
一位勇者
a woman of strength,
一位闪耀的新娘
and a bride of astonishing beauty.
我的夫人
My wife.
克莱尔 弗雷泽
Claire Fraser.
你不用怕我 克莱尔
You needn't be afraid of me, Claire.
我不会强迫你的
I wasna planning to suddenly force myself on you.
我没这么想过
Never thought you would.
我有问题想问你
I have questions.
我就知道你会有的
Ah, I suppose you do...
在这种情形之下
under the circumstances.
你想知道什么
What is it you want to know?
嗯 我
Well, I, um...
不管了
What the hell.
我就直截了当的说吧
Might as well come straight out with it.
你为什么愿意娶我
Why did you agree to marry me?
我的意思是杜戈尔没有给我什么选择 但你
I mean, Dougal didn't give me much of a choice, but you...
我也没什么选择
Well, I... I didna see I had much choice either.
我们时间不够了
We do not have much time.
队长要我们明天把毕彻姆夫人交出去
Captain Randall is expecting Mistress Beauchamp
给他
to be delivered to him tomorrow.
我们就快
Now, we are all about to embark on a boat
无路可走了
built entirely of paper.
只有法律才能让克莱尔摆脱
The letter of the law is the only thing
兰德尔的魔爪
keeping Claire out of Randall 's hands.
如果真的要按照法律来 那我们
And so if it is to work, then we have to follow it
必须一步一步来
to the letter.
婚礼必须马上举行
The marriage must be consummated right away
证人如果不在屋子里 就必须发誓
and witnesses must swear that they were present
他在屋子里
in the building if not in the room itself.
克莱尔知道这一切么
Does Claire know about all this?
她没有发言权
She has no say in the matter.
你不会是要强暴吧
I thought you didn't want with rape, Dougal.
不是 我说服她
No rape. Persuasion.
她是个聪明的姑娘
She's a smart lass.
她最终会明白事情的原因
She'll see the reason for it in the end,
但是两个年轻人之间
but there can be no secret agreements
不能有秘密协议
between the two of ya,
你明明没有秘密还是得说你有
you saying that you have when you have not.
此外 我能想到我这一生中
Besides, I can think of worse things in my lifetime
抓着她的奶子操她
than holding onto that pair of sweet ciochan,
-更糟糕的事情  -好的 够了
- plunging my cock... - Yeah, enough!
如果克莱尔真的会成为我妻子
If Claire does become my wife,
你谈到她想到她的时候 能别把她当成妓女的话
I'll thank you to stop talking and thinking of her
我会很感激你
like some common whore.
嘿 如果
Hey! If?
没有如果 小子
There is no if about this, laddie.
现在 她挨了兰德尔几拳
Now, she took a few blows at the hands of Randall
还能保持沉默 这已经超出
and kept silent, which is a fair sight more
我都普通女性的期望了
than I 'd expect of any ordinary woman.
但你知道兰德尔的
But you know Randall.
你知道他能力
You know what he's capable of.
如果她再落入他的手里
What do you think'll happen to her
你觉得她会有怎样的下场
if she falls into his hands again?
因此你娶我是为了保护我的安全
So you married me to keep me safe.
是的
Aye.
这是主要原因
That's the gist of it.
你有我的姓氏
You have my name,
我的宗族
my clan,
我的家庭
my family.
并且 如果必要
And, if necessary,
还有我身体的保护
the protection of my body as well.
和我谈谈你的家族
Tell me about your family.
要追溯到第几代
How many generations back?
你父母亲的就可以了
Your parents will do.
好吧
Aye.
我的父亲姓弗雷泽
My father was a Fraser.
当然 了
Of course.
是现任领主同父异母的弟弟
A younger half-brother to the present master...
还有科勒姆和杜格尔 我的母亲是艾琳 麦肯齐
Colum and Dougal... my mother was Aileen Mackenzie,
科勒姆和杜格尔的姐姐
the elder sister of Colum and Dougal.
科勒姆希望我母亲嫁给马尔科姆 格兰特
Colum wished my mother to marry Malcolm Grant.
我的阿姨珍妮特去世了 跟我母亲一样
My aunt Janet is dead, like my mother,
但我的阿姨伊俄卡斯忒
but my aunt Jocasta...
我的父亲一直看着我长大
I had my father see me grow up.
我对此总是心存感谢
I was always grateful for that.
很显然 这是在转移话题
It was a distraction, to be sure,
但我们两个都觉得很愉快
but a welcome one for both of us.
当他告诉我他的家族历史时
When he told me his family history,
我也告诉了他我的
I reciprocated in kind...
我们共度接下来的几小时
and we each spent the next several hours
喝酒 聊天 还有
drinking and talking and...
第一次 大概的了解彼此
generally getting to know
新的配偶
our new spouses for the first time.
和女孩在一起的第一晚 每个人等着
First evening with the girl, everyone waited
想看她是否会接受她
to see would she take him or no?
他很迷人
He was charming,
一个天生的讲故事的人 像大多数苏格兰人一样
a born storyteller, like most Scots.
她让马尔科姆 格兰特离开
She told Malcolm Grant off.
最终他只好回家
And he headed home as a result.
随着时间的流逝 我开始放松了
As the hours passed, I began to relax
最终开始享受
and eventually to enjoy myself.
你母亲呢
And your mother?
她和我父亲就在300个族人眼皮子底下
She and my father slipped out of the castle
偷偷地从城堡溜走了
right under the noses of 300 clansmen.
我的父亲很爱说那个故事
And my father loved telling that story.
我跟你说了滚开 蠢货
I told you to stand back, ye coof ye!
我可不要在外头徘徊
I wasn't gonna ponce around outside the door, was I?
等着他们回答
- Waiting for them to answer...
我们来只是喝杯茶什么的
like we were just coming by for a nice cup of tea.
你究竟在干什么
And just what are you doing?
杜格尔派我们来看看你们是不是 呃
Dougal sent us up to see if ye'd, uh...
-你懂吗 -现在 谁才是蠢货
- y'ken? - Now, who's the coof?
他们还穿着衣服呢
They've still got their clothes on.
-出去 -你穿着衣服也可以
- Get out. - You can still do it
-继续做 -我知道
- with your clothes on. - I know that,
但新婚夜可不行
but not on your wedding night!
我只是希望能
I was just hoping to get
偷看下她的胸部
a wee keek at her breasts.
他们是你的亲戚吗
They're related to you?
只有鲁柏特才是
Rupert only.
远房表兄弟
Distant cousin.
太晚了
It's getting rather late.
也许我们该上床了
Perhaps we should go to bed?
上床
To bed...
还是睡觉
or to sleep?
你说呢
Well...
不管怎样 你穿着束腹
Either way you're... not likely to sleep
没法睡觉的 所以我
in your corset, so I 'll...
我来帮你
I'll help you with the...
解开带子吧
the laces and such.
先脱裙子
Skirts first.
是的
Aye.
该我了
It's my turn.
你在哪学到那样子接吻的
Where did you learn to kiss like that?
我只说过我是个处男
I said I was a virgin...
可没说是个修道士
not a monk.
如果我需要指导 我会问的
If I need guidance... I'll ask.
吉米 你压痛我了
Jamie, you're crushing me.
跟你想象的一样吗
So was it like you thought it would be?
差不多
Almost.
我还以为
I thought...
不 算了
no, never mind.
什么 告诉我呗
What? Tell me.
跟你说了你会笑我的
You'll laugh at me.
我保证不会笑你
Promise, I won't laugh.
我不知道你喜欢面对面的
I didna realize you did it face-to-face.
我还以为你喜欢背入式的
I thought you must do it the back way,
你知道 像马一样
you know, like... like horses, ye ken.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我知道 我说过我不会笑
I know, I promised I wouldn't laugh.
我想问你个问题
I'll ask you a question.
尽管问
Of course.
你喜欢吗
Did you like it?
额
Huh.
嗯
Hmm.
看来穆塔夫说得对
Murtagh was right about that, then.
穆塔夫
Murtagh?
他说一般女人都不会喜欢这种姿势
He said women generally do not care for it.
他和鲁伯特
Well, he and Rupert.
还有内德
And Ned.
他们为昨晚的事提了很多主意
They offered a lot of advice on the subject last night.
我喜欢 杰米
I did like it, Jamie.
事情就是这样
There it was.
我变成了重婚者和荡妇
Not only was I a bigamist and an adulteress,
而我居然还很享受
but I 'd enjoyed it.
我去拿点东西吃
I need to get some food.
克莱尔 等等
Claire, wait.
等等
Wait!
嘿
Hey!
嘿 小妞 如果你现在还能跑能跳
Hey, lass, if you're still able to walk,
说明杰米昨晚没有尽到责任哦
Jamie isna doing his duty by ye!
如果她让你精疲力尽了 杰米
If she's worn out already, Jamie,
我会很乐意代替你的位置的
I'll be more than happy to fill your place.
住嘴 让我们清静点
Bit of a curse and give us peace.
你最好回去
Better go back inside, Sassenach.
他们在尽兴之前是不会停止取笑我们的
Until they've had their fun, they'll no leave us alone.
哦 杰米 初夜感觉怎么样
Oh, Jamie, how was your first time?
你有没有流血
Did ye bleed?
没有 但是你快要了 死贱人 闭上你的臭嘴
No, but you will, you bugger, ye dinna haud yer wheesht.
嘿 你是享受了
Hey, while you're filling your face,
也许我也可以上楼去享受啊
maybe I 'll go upstairs and fill mine, hey?
也许 我给你一拳 怎么样
Maybe... maybe I'll fill it with my fist, huh?
好了 伙计们 戏看完了
All right, lads, show's over.
我们没必要熬夜了
Dinna need to stay up any longer.
希望你也有机会熬夜啊
Aye, but let's hope you do.
你干嘛不给钱去享受洞房花烛夜呢
Why don't you buy yourself
就像内德一样
a wedding night like Ned did?
这是他洞房的唯一方法
It's the only way he'll ever get one.
谢谢
Thank you.
别以为你这样谢我就够了
Don't think ye've thanked me properly.
我可是把你调到别处去让你能施展才能
For finding you somewhere better to stick yer cock
你才可以逃出那个马厩
than the fillies in the stable.
谢谢 我是真心的
Thank you. Truly.
过来坐会
Come on, sit yourself down awhile.
你也不想表现的太热情了想要回去找你的
You don't want to appear too keen to return to your...
你的新娘吧
your bride.
他真的这么说
Did he really say that?
是啊 他说 你不能让一个女的感觉到
Aye, he said, "You never want to let a woman see
你拼命想讨好她
"You're too eager to please her.
这会让她骑在你头上
Gives her too much power."
真的吗
Really?
你是怎么回答的
And what did you have to say to that?
我说我已经完全被你骑在头上了
I said I was completely under yer power
我也很乐意这么做
and happy to be there.
还有威士忌吗
Is there any more whiskey?
随时都有
Always.
谢谢
Thank you.
对不起
Sorry.
是什么意思
What does that mean?
我的棕发姑娘
"My brown-haired lass."
棕色看起来很沉闷 我一直是这么认为的
Rather a dull color, brown, I've always thought.
不
No.
不 一点也不沉闷
No, not dull at all.
就像是 水在燃烧的颜色
It's like the... the water in a burn,
冲刷着石头的时候
The way it ruffles down the rocks.
阳光照进黑暗
Dark in the wavy spots with...
折射出了微微褐色的波浮光点
wee bits of auburn when the sun touches it.
我看见了
I see, um...
看见了宴会时穿的短裙
see a new kilt for the occasion.
啊
Aye.
弗雷泽家族颜色
The Fraser colors.
你是在哪弄来的
Where did you get it?
嗯 额
Huh. Ah. Ha.
很贵吗
Did it cost you dear?
不贵 只是费时间和口水而已
It cost nothing but time and conversation.
它是属于弗雷泽一个寡妇的丈夫的
The clothes belonged to the husband of a Fraser widow
离这里大概五英里
about five miles from here.
她丈夫是在十年前死的
Died about ten years ago.
我敢说是被她念叨多了才会英年早逝
I wager she talked the poor bugger into an early grave.
明晚前就得还给她
She wants them back by tomorrow night.
-为什么 -我没问
- Why? - I didna ask.
我差点就忘记带回来了
I almost didn't bring the damn things back to you anyway.
村里到处都是英国士兵
The village is crawling with redcoats.
我知道
I'm well aware.
要不然我就自己准备结婚时穿的衣服了
Otherwise I 'd be collecting my own wedding clothes.
你认为你走出这里
And what do you think would happen
他们发现了会怎么对你
when you prance out of here
你头发红色 身材又这么魁梧
with your red hair and your muckle size
还穿着弗雷泽的衣服
wearing Fraser colors?
这跟在你的背上画个靶子没什么两样
You might as well paint a target on your back.
我只准备结一次婚 慕士塔格
I plan to be wed but one time, Muztagh.
所以我会采取一种让我妈妈都感到自豪方式
So I 'll do so in a way that would make my mother proud.
真是的
Hud.
你了解她吗
What do you make of her?
比彻姆夫人
Mistress Beauchamp.
她不错
She'll do.
我想我妈妈会同意的
I think my mother would have approved.
你觉得我像个吉普赛人吗
Do I look like a gypsy to you, huh?
能跟神灵沟通
Able to commune with the spirits?
你还带着胸针吗
Have you still got your brooch?
你妈妈的笑容是那么的甜美
Your mother had the sweetest smile.
看到她的笑容 能让人觉得温暖
Would warm a man to the backbone just to see it.
卡瑞的笑容也很美
Claire's smile is just as sweet.
给
Here.
穆塔夫说的吗
Murtagh said that?
哈
Ha.
我没想到会还有什么事能这么浪漫
I wouldn't have expected anything quite so romantic.
大智若愚吧 懂吗
Well, still waters run deep, ye ken?
他是弗雷泽家族的人还是麦肯齐家族的人
Is he a Fraser or a Mackenzie?
穆塔夫 费茨基布斯 弗雷泽
Murtagh Fitzgibbons Fraser.
我很惊讶杜戈尔会等他给你拿裙子
I'm surprised Dougal waited for him to go get your kilt.
他那么着急的一个人
He was in such a hurry.
他是性急 但是我让他慢着点
He was, but I slowed him down.
我答应你
I'll do it.
但是我有三个条件
But I have three conditions.
哦 天啊 杀了你们还更容易些
Ah, Christ, it would be easier if I kill ye both.
这很难解释
Much harder to explain.
第一 我们要正正当当的结婚
First, we must be wed properly.
在教堂里举行婚礼
In a church.
神父进去之前
Before a priest.
已经十点半了 但这个家伙还赖
Half past ten. And this one still burrowing
在被窝里
under his blankets.
哦 天啊 神父
Oh, Christ, father!
我没告诉你不要对着被人打喷嚏吗
Did I no just tell you to aim it off to the side?
如果他不把我从床上挖起来就不会有这问题了
There'd be no problem if he had left me in my bed.
我们只要你服务一个小时
We only need your services for an hour,
然后你就能钻回你的被窝了
th you can coorie back doon under your blankets.
-他说他不干 -我可没这么说
- He says he won't do it. - That is no what I said.
我说在宣读到结婚预告之前
I said I canna perform a wedding
我不能主持婚礼
until after the banns have been read.
但这需要三星期
But that would take three weeks.
我们没有三天时间
We don't have three days.
那我就不能为你们主持婚礼了
Then I won't be performing your wedding.
我也有把刀子 必要时我也会用
I have a knife too, and I'm no afraid to use it.
我想你是寡不敌众的 神父
I believe we have you outnumbered, father.
是 但你们都不是神父
Aye, but neither of ye a priest.
杀了我 你在方圆几里之内都
Kill me, and you have no one for milesund
找不到其他神父来主持婚礼了
to perform a wedding.
在我来之前 好好宣读圣经
"Till I come, give attendance to reading,
劝勉和传教
to exhortation and to doctrine."
出自 提摩太前书 第4章 第13节
1 Timothy, chapter 4, verse 13.
按教堂教义 在举行婚礼之前
Church doctrine says before there can be any wedding,
结婚双方的名字必须连续三天三次
the names of the contracted parties must be publicly
对外公示
announced three times on three consecutive...
听着 你个懒鬼
Look, you dozy smout!
你不是在法律之下 但在恩典之下
"Yer not under the law... but under grace."
出自 罗马书 第6章第14节
Romans 6:14.
如果你是从拜恩神父那里学教义问答书
If you'd learned your catechism from father Bain,
那么你也该学学 圣经诗
you'd ken your bible verses too.
要注意你自身和自身的教义
"Take heed unto thyself, and unto the doctrine.
持之以恒 才能解救你自身
"Continue in them: for in doing this thou shalt both
以及那些听从于你的人
save thyself and them that hear thee."
出自 提摩太前书 第4章
1 Timothy, chapter 4,
第16节
verse 16.
不要忘记款待陌生人
"Be not forgetful to entertain strangers,
因为有人因此在不经意间款待了天使
for thereby some have entertained angels unawares."
不要被各式各样的怪异教义引入歧途
"Be not carried about with divers and strange doctrines."
-你把诗句弄混了 -这都来自 希伯来书
- You're mixing up the verses. - It's all Hebrews.
-你不能这么做 -够了
- Well, ye canna do that. - Enough!
这里比女巫的乳头还冷
It's colder than a witch's tit in here.
不管有没有结婚预告
Ye'll perform the ceremony tomorrow,
你明天都有主持仪式 否则你就主持你自己的最后仪式吧
banns or no, or you'll be performing yo last rite.
来啊 杀了我
Go ahead, kill me.
就算我葬身火海
Even if I burn in the fiery pit,
都好过在这痛苦的冰窖中
it'd be better than spending one more Sunday
再度过一周
in this miserable freezing box.
给你单独准备间房间怎样
How would you like your own proper windows?
杜戈尔说那个小个子立马就问
Dougal said that the wee man barely skipped a beat
我们什么时候
before asking what time we would like
要举行仪式
the ceremony to begin.
教堂和金钱 有些东西永远都不会变
Church and money: some things don't change.
-嗯 -给
- Mm. - Here.
你的下一个条件是什么
What was your next condition?
如果你让我比完这场比赛
If ye'd have let me finish the game,
我就能替我们赢回一枚戒指
I woulda won us a proper ring.
好吧 这就是杰米要的
Well, this is what Jamie wants,
既然他决定结婚 那这就是他应得的
and since it's his wedding, this is what he'll get.
-日安 -日安
- Good day to you. - Good day.
你是铁匠吗
Are you the blacksmith?
他当然是铁匠  你个蠢货
Of course he's the blacksmith, ye great gob.
我们想要一个戒指
We want a ring made.
-一个婚戒 -给一个女孩的
- A wedding ring. - For a lass.
-你能打吗 -一个婚戒
- Can you do it? - A wedding ring?
应该可以
I suppose.
我在后面有一些银
I've got some silver in the back.
不 用这个做
No. Make it from this.
这是把很好的钥匙
It's a perfectly good key.
熔了它有点可惜
It would be a shame to melt that down.
哦 别全熔了
Oh, dinna melt it down.
新郎希望你可以留着
The groom wants you to keep the mmm...
插入锁的那部分
the part that goes into the lock
还有 那个
and... the...
末尾的部分
part on the other end.
钥匙齿和钥匙把
the blade and the bow.
- 对对 钥匙齿和钥匙把 - 你不也不知道
- Aye, the blade and the bow. - You didna ken that.
好吧
Aye.
可以做
It can be done.
下星期来拿
Next week.
- 今天就要 - 那要额外收费
- Today. - It'll cost ye.
把钱给他
Give him the money.
好吧
All right.
你说你会付一半的钱
Ye said ye'd pay half.
你要没把我从赌局上拉出来 我肯定会付的
I would have, had you not taken me out of the game.
钥匙
A key.
开什么的钥匙
Key to what?
没什么
Nothing.
我在我毛皮袋里挖到的
It was just something I had in my sporran.
你第三个条件是什么
What was your third condition?
我留给奈德了
I left that to Ned.
这件怎么样 喜欢吗
What about this one? Do you like it?
小姐 表这样
M-mistress, please.
我是来这买衣服的 不是女人
I'm here to find a dress, not a woman.
我喜欢这件
I like this one.
这件的颜色我最喜欢了
This one's my favorite color.
- 你喜欢吗 - 嗯
- Do you like it? - Mm.
- 看看背面 - 嗯
- Look what it does at the back. - Mm-hmm.
- 有蕾丝边哦 - 嗯
- It laces up. - Mm-hmm.
- 那你喜欢这件吗 - 额
- Do you want this one, then? - Um...
还有你喜欢衣服里面的这个吗
Wouldn't you like to take me out of this one?
新娘不是个
The... the bride isn't a...
- 不检点的女人 - 对 是的
- a woman of loose morals? - Aye, yes.
她 她可不能在婚礼上穿这个
She's a... she can't be wearing that on her wedding day.
那么你可不应该在妓院
Then maybe ye shouldn't be shopping for a dress
买婚纱
at a whorehouse.
我有适合你的婚纱
I have something might suit ye.
走开 快
Get back, back now.
不然我可要拧你们耳朵了
Or I 'll clout your ears for ye.
这件可是来自一位我们都熟知的贵族的恩赐
Courtesy of a certain lord with whom we are familiar.
他在伦敦为他女人买的
His lordship bought it in London for his lady.
在回家的路上 在斯特林一家酒馆
On his way home, he lost the rest of his money
丢了所有的钱
at the tables in Stirling,
所以当他来光顾我们这儿的时候
so when he came by us for his usual visit,
欲火熊熊 却囊中羞涩
he was long on desire but a wee bit short on clink.
他想用这件婚纱来交易 我接受了
He proposed a trade and I accepted.
从来没穿过
Never been worn.
等候一位绅士来取走它
Was waiting for a gentleman to visit before putting it on,
不过我觉得还是不拿出来为好
but I suppose it's best I never did.
没有女人愿意在婚礼上
No lass should wear another woman's dress
穿别的女人的衣服
on her wedding day.
好吧 这件非常合适
Well, that'll do nicely.
收你一先令
Cost ye a schilling.
好吧好吧好吧
Fine, fine, fine.
你买完就要走吗
Oh, must you run off straight away?
姑娘们还需要几分钟时间来包一下衣服
It will take the girls a few minutes to wrap it up.
以防天气骤变
Protect it from the whether, ye ken?
我们可以为您提供一些娱乐活动
Perhaps we could offer ye some entertainment
在你等待的时候
in the meantime?
- 来嘛 - 慢慢来嘛
- Come on. - Now, just slowly.
别这么急
Not too fast.
拜托
Oh, come on.
你肯定是胡编乱造的
Now you're just making things up.
没有 我把奈德的话一模一样说给你听了
No, I-I told it to you exactly as Ned told it to me.
当时他笑得像只摇尾巴狗
Grinning like a dog with twa tails
满脸容光焕发
and beaming red the whole time.
你看到婚礼上那个妓女了吗
Did ye not see the strumpet at the wedding?
- 噢 就是那个妓女啊 - 对的
- Oh, so that's who that was. - Aye.
我当时都不知道原来还有这档子事儿
I had no idea that all that was going on.
是啊
That's right.
你还没告诉我你都做什么了
Ye've not told me what you were doing all day.
啊
Ah.
嘿 站起来 小姑娘
Hey, on your feet, lass.
你可不会想烂醉如泥地
You hardly wanna get married
去结婚
looking like a melted candle.
烂醉如啥
Like a what?
哦天啊
Oh, god.
那么 你一点也记不起婚礼上的事儿了
So, do ye no remember anything of your own wedding?
- 事实上 我记得一点 - 啊
- As a matter of fact, I do. - Ah.
记得我那天宿醉未醒这件事儿 至少
I did have a monstrous hangover, though.
哈
Huh.
我却记得每个一时刻 每一分每一秒
I remember every moment, every second.
我永远忘不了走出教堂的时候
I'll never forget when I came out of the church
第一眼看到你
and saw you for the first time.
感觉好像我走出门阴云密布
It was as if I stepped outside on a cloudy day
突然一下子就云开见日了
and suddenly the sun came out.
我永远效劳于你 女士
Your servant, Madam.
我不能嫁给你
I can't marry you.
我连你叫什么都不知道
I don't even know your real name.
我叫弗雷泽
It's Fraser.
詹姆斯 亚历山大
James Alexander
马尔科姆 麦肯齐 弗雷泽
Malcolm Mackenzie Fraser.
克莱尔 伊丽莎白 毕彻姆
Claire Elizabeth Beauchamp.
好吧 你们俩如果聊完了
Well, if you two are quite finished...
那我们继续吧
let's get on with it.
你一点也不记得了吗
So you don't remember any of this?
还记得一点点
Not all of it,
有件事儿还记得非常清晰
but some things are very clear.
我 詹姆斯 亚历山大 马尔科姆 麦肯齐 弗雷泽
I, James Alexander Malcolm Mackenzie Fraser
愿意娶 克莱尔 伊丽莎白 毕彻姆
take, thee, Claire Elizabeth Beauchamp,
作为我的妻子
to be my wedded wife,
从今开始 执子之手 与子偕老
to have and to hold from this day forth,
同甘共苦 生死相依
for better or for worse, in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
till death us do part.
我 克莱尔 伊丽莎白 毕彻姆
I, Claire Elizabeth Beauchamp
愿意嫁给
take, thee,
詹姆斯 亚历山大 马尔科姆 麦肯齐 弗雷泽
James Alexander Malcolm Mackenzie Fraser
作为我的丈夫
to be my wedded husband.
从今开始 执子之手 与子偕老
To have and to hold from this day...
生死相依
in sickness and in health...
至死不渝
till death us do part.
准备好戒指了吗
Do you have the ring?
是的
Aye.
阿门
Amen.
跟着我说
Say the words after me.
这些话到底啥意思
What exactly did the words mean?
我们自此骨肉相连
"You are blood of my blood and bone of my bone."
我奉献我的生命 我们合而为一
"I give you my body that we two may be one."
我奉献我的灵魂
"I give you my spirit...
直到生命的尽头
"Till our life shall be done."
现在你可以吻你的新娘了
You may kiss yer bride.
当时你吻我的样子
When you kissed me like that,
看来 你应该并不遗憾
well, maybe you weren't so sorry
嫁给我
to be marrying me after all.
把衣服脱了
Take off your shirt.
我想看看你
I want to look at you.
好吧那么
Well, then...
要公平才行
fair is fair.
也请你把衣服脱了
Take off yours as well.
你过去从没见过裸体的女人吗
Have you never seen a naked woman before?
见过 不过从没这么靠近看过
Aye, but not one so close.
而且没有看过属于我的身体
And not one that's mine.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不是故意弄疼你的
I didna mean to hurt you.
你没有弄疼我
You didn't.
你确定
You sure?
- 是的 - 哈
- Yes. - Ha.
我不知道女人还会
I dinna know women could...
每次都会这样吗
Does it happen every time?
除非那个男人是位很棒的情人
Only if the man is a very good lover.
可你那么娇弱 我不想弄疼你
But you're so small. I didna want to hurt you.
- 你在做什么 - 别动
- What are you doing? - Stay still.
- 疼吗 - 有点
- Does that hurt? - Little bit.
要我停下吗
Do you want me to stop?
不
No.
你说什么
What did you say?
我还以为我的心烧起来了
"I thought my heart was gonna burst."
弗雷泽夫人
Mrs. Fraser.
- 你这么晚才回来 - 是的
- You're out late. - Aye.
我刚见完兰德尔上尉回来
I'm just back from seeing Captain Randall.
我和他分享了愉快的消息
I shared with him the happy news
跟他说你不会再听从他的指示了
that you're no longer at his beck and call.
他说什么了
What did he say?
他说你说的蠢话
That there are likely limits even to your tolerance
毫无底线
for foul language.
我觉得他应该不会
I don't suppose he means
采取进一步行动吧
to take any further steps about it?
我觉得不会
I shouldn't think so.
他还有比跟一个放荡英格兰女人纠缠
He's got more important things to worry about
更重要的事儿要忙
than chasing after one stray Sassenach,
不论她有多漂亮
no matter how pretty.
他还不会至于绑架科勒姆侄子的老婆
And he's got better sense than to rile Colum
来激怒他
by kidnapping his nephew's wife.
那我可以舒口气了
That's comforting to know.
我很赞许你做了本分的事
I commend you for doing your duty.
不过这些也不妨碍你去找点别的乐子
But it needn't stop you from sampling other pleasures.
你是我见过最非凡的女人 克莱尔
I find you to be the most singular woman, Claire.
我是杰米的妻子
I'm Jamie's wife.
晚上好 夫人 杜戈尔
Evening, mistress, Dougal.
晚上好 鲁伯特
Good evening, Rupert.
我想谢谢你的好意
I would like to thank you for your kindness towards me.
戒指很漂亮
The... the ring is magnificent.
哦 好吧 不用客气
Oh, well, you're welcome.
由衷祝贺你
And a most hearty congratulations to you
新婚快乐
on your wedding day.
谢谢
Thank you.
啊 小杰米可能没有什么经验
Ah, young Jamie may no have much experience,
不过这个女人看起来被管教得很好
but that one looks like well ridden.
这又是为什么
What was that fer?
- 检查一下马匹 - 我检查过了
- Check the horses. - I've already done it.
再去检查一遍
Do it again.
这是苏格兰珍珠
They're Scotch pearls.
我母亲的
They belonged to my mother.
现在属于我的妻子了
And now they belong to my wife.
这是她留给我的仅存的几样东西之一
They're one of the few things I have left of her.
对我来说弥足珍贵
And very precious to me.
就像你一样 克莱尔
As are you, Claire.
我们楼下见
I'll meet you downstairs.
如果我再不吃点东西
If I don't get something to eat soon,
我就要咬你了
I might have to take a bite out of you.
我觉得你咬过我了
I believe you've already done that.
我想马上再这么咬你
And I look forward to doing it again soon.
你也快下来哦
Don't be long.
不然除了面包屑 什么都不会剩下
There'll be nothing left but crumbs.